Association for Research and Enlightenment Collection
The Edgar Cayce Foundation
- Publications, 1931 2015
  - Box 6
    - A.R.E. News, 1976; Folder 6:4; Landers, Olive; Sparrow, Gregory Scott; Banks, Leigh; January, 1976 -Foundation Sponsors Trip to Middle East -ARE Welcomes Publishing Consultant (Nan Comstock) -Feedline -A Member's Response (Elizabeth Henderson) -New File Available -File Available on Health and Beauty -Research Department Offers Growth Experience (Workbook-Questionnaire) -Schedule of Upcoming Events -Study Group News -Health and Beauty -Library Serves Community -ARE Offers Wilderness Retreats -Over the Wall -ARE Library News -Library Building Fund Report -Souls Slip Too! (Soul Retrogression Part I circulating file) -Ruth Gets a New Pole (new flagpole at Headquarters) February, 1976 -Atlantic University Launches Dream Journal (Henry Reed) -Feedline -Guest Column (Kenneth Skidmore) -Youth Activities Sponsors Tour -Violet Shelley Resigns from Editorial Post -Membership Message -Study Group News -Wilderness Trips Require Confirmation -Over the Wall -Astrologer Researches Readings (Alexander Markin) -ARE Recognizes Volunteers -Congress '76 Approaches -Health and Beauty -ARE Library News -Library Building Fund Report -ESP Research Project Planned for Fall March, 1976 -Atlantic University Looks Ahead -Meditation Taught in the Field -Feedline -A Member's Response (T.C. Hubaut) -Plans Shape Up for Youth Study Tour -ARE Introduces New Regional Representatives (Fred Hall, Tom Ehmke) -Over the Wall -Study Group News -ARE Features Conference with Dr. David Zink -Nurses Cultivate Healing Skills (Arline Mandas) -Health and Beauty -Large Print Edition of A Search for God Now Available -Camp Season Approaches -ARE Library News -Library Building Fund Report -Membership Message -Hieroglyphics Course Offered April, 1976 -Noted Atlantis Researcher Lectures for ARE (David D. Zink) -Spring Conference Features Death-Rebirth Theme -Feedline -Guest Column (Meredith Ann Puryear) -Toward a Metaphysical Bicentennial -Study Group News -ARE Hosts Second Spa Week -Over the Wall -New Booklet Features Lucid Dreaming -Health and Beauty -Camp Van Breathes Its Last -Membership Message -ARE Library News -Library Building Fund Report -A.U. Serves California Contingent May, 1976 -ARE Appoints National Field Representative (Edward Sloan, Jr.) -Are You Coming to Congress Week? -Feedline -Guest Column (Mark Thurston) -Toward a Metaphysical Bicentennial (Robert Krajenke) -Deadline Set for Yucatan Trip -Introductory Film Completed -Summer Courses on Group Dynamics Offered -Study Group News -Over the Wall -Headquarters Youth Camp Plans Summer Activities -Library Hosts Gnostic Exhibit -Weekend Conference Features His Holiness Faquir Dayal -Regional Representatives: Introducing Rachel Runnels -ARE Camp Offers Mountain Hikes -ARE Library News -Library Building Fund Report -Membership Message June, 1976 -Producer Purchases Option on Cayce Movie (Henry C. Gellis) -Dr. Puryear Assumes Full-Time Role with Atlantic University -Feedline -Toward a Metaphysical Bicentennial -Dream Readings Expand the Library Series -Health and Beauty -Study Group News -Sundance Gains Momentum -Research Project Features Psychic Development -Dr. Zink Named Explorer of the Year -Many Mansions in Icelandic edition -William Fix Casts New Light on Ancient Egypt -ARE Hosts Professional Conference -ARE Library News -Library Building Fund Report -Gnosticism Poses Pertinent Questions Membership Message -Clinic Bulletin July, 1976 -Gardeners Sustain Nature's Needs -Membership Book Features Application of A Search for God -Feedline -Findhorn Demonstrates New Age Ideal -Toward a Metaphysical Bicentennial -Membership Message -Secret Dead Sea Scroll to be Published -Study Group News -Bicentennial Bonus -Annual Chiropractic Seminar Approaches (Clio Dixon, D.C.) -Health and Beauty -Meditation Pyramid Constructed at Headquarters -Cayce Recipe Book Nears Publication -ARE Library News -Library Building Fund Report -Staff Bowlers Raise Funds for Library -Prison Program Offers Pen Pal Opportunities August, 1976 -'76 Congress Shares Spirit of Freedom -Feedline -Guest Column (William Fix) -Creativity Lab Sparks Unfoldment -Membership Message -Japanese Scientist to Speak at ARE (Tsuneyo Kamoshida, M.D.) -Children's Library Facilities Expand -Study Group News -Finalized Conferences Announced -Congress Recommendations for Publications -A Conferee's Experience At Virginia Beach -ARE Offers Third Cayce-Reilly Spa Week -ARE Library News -Library Building Fund Report -Over the Wall September, 1976 -ARE Consolidates Teams Program (Lynn Elwell, ARE Teams Coordinator) -Congress Recommendations for Study Groups -Feedline -A Letter from Cayce (Edgar Cayce) -What Price Dreams? -ARE Announces Fall Programs -Study Group News -Sechrists Plan Tour to Middle East -Over the Wall -Health and Beauty -A Report on Project Groups -ARE Seeks Volunteer Typists -Nell Sends Thanks -Atlantic University Completes Fifth Year -ARE Library News -Library Building Fund Report -Membership Message -Affirmation Used by All October, 1976 -Conferees Impressed with Variety in Conferences -AU Announces Publication of Sundance Dream Journal -Feedline -Guest Column (Scott Sparrow) -Fall Programs -Health and Beauty -Study Group News -Membership Message -Library Series Expands -Garden Contest Winner Announced -ARE Plans New Year's Conference -Over the Wall -Testimonies Requested -Library Builds Welcome Bond -ARE Library News -Library Building Fund Report -Congress Recommendations for Education November, 1976 -Endocrine System Studied At Health Seminar -Feedline -Retreat Provides Relaxation -Over the Wall -Study Group News -A Member's Self-Rehabilitation (Joseph Schmid) -Message from Study Group Six -Membership Message -Pagano Uses Reading's Treatments (John Pagano, D.C.) -Health and Beauty -Annual Research Nears Completion -New Regional Rep Appointed: Bud McFall -ARE Library News -Library Building Fund Report -Publications Catalogue Off The Press -Braille Library Needs Assistance December, 1976 -Spa Week Stresses Balance -Japanese Group Visits ARE -Feedline -Study Group News -Health and Beauty -Over the Wall -C.O.R.E. Holds Annual Meeting (Council on Research and Education for the ARE Clinic) -Membership Message -International Corner -Conference Calendar Mailed -Clinic Program -ARE Library News -Library Building Fund Report -Library Gains New Staff Member (Stephen Jordan) -Winter Programs -Camp Applications Available
    - A.R.E. News, 1977; Folder 6:5; Landers, Olive; Banks, Leigh; Brittell, Katherine A.; January, 1977 -If Ye Will But Meditate...281-41 -Planning to Attend June Congress? -A Staff Meeting Over 50 Years Ago... -Feedline -David Zink Tells of Explorations -Membership Message -New Regional Representative Appointed: Jim Carrino -International Corner -Braille Library Receives Gift -Winter Programs -Over the Wall -Which Wilderness? -Study Group News -ARE Library News -Library Building Fund Report -Health and Beauty February, 1977 -ARE Steps into the Past (Egypt-Jordan-Israel Tour) -Feedline -Does God Play Games? (Marcus Bach lecture) -International Corner (Margaret Mottershead) -Programs Across the Nation -'77 Congress Approaches -Study Group News -Plan for the Wilderness -Easter Conference Nears -ARE Library News -Library Building Fund Report -Membership Message -Annual Symposiums Scheduled March, 1977 -AU Designs '77 Sessions -Coming to Camp? -Feedline -ARE Research Published -New Year's Conference Brings Crowd -Membership Message -Bruce Hungerford obituary -Marshalls Hotel Work-Study applications -Congress Consolidates June Plans -Library Announces New Book List -Library Building Fund Report -ARE Programs Across the Nation -Health and Beauty -Over the Wall -Guest Word -Study Group News -International Corner April, 1977 -Press Rolls Ahead with New Manager (Dal Barker) -AU Releases Second Sundance Dream Journal -Feedline -Headquarters Announcements -Study Group News -Over the Wall: An Interview with Hugh Lynn Cayce -Clap If You Believe... -Vows Exchanged at Winter Weddings (Charles Thomas and Leslie Cayce; Lynn and Scott Sparrow; David and Lynne Smith) -International Corner -ARE Programs Across the Nation -Program Corrections -Camp Announces Youth Week -ARE Library News -Library Building Fund Report -Membership Message -Braille Note May, 1977 -Hopkinsville Celebrates Cayce Centennial -Feedline -Guest Column: Impressions of a Wilderness Trip (Anita Daskam) -Wilderness Note -Clinic Bulletin -Miss Price Observes 80th (Edith Ballinger Price) -Membership Message -Class Photographs Emotions -Health and Beauty -ARE Programs Across the Nation -Conferences Offer College Credit -John Sanford to Speak at Asilomar -Library Building Fund Report -Study Group News -Extrasensory Summer Projects -Over the Wall June, 1977 -ARE Clinic Expands Facilities -Conference Features Dr. Ritchie (Dr. George G. Ritchie) -Feedline -H.L. Cayce Recuperates at Home -Health and Beauty -Dream for Atlantic U. -International Corner -ARE Headquarters Programs -Reincarnation Date Revised -Bach to Speak -Last Call - Family Camp! -Over the Wall -I Am Clapping... -Earth Changes File Available -ARE Library News -Library Building Fund Report -Study Group News -Membership Message July, 1977 -Library Purchases A.J. Davis Collection -Combine Vacation with August Conference -Feedline -Tour Mexico -Membership Notice -Business and Professional Conferences -Rolling Thunder's Son Visits ARE -Chiropractic Seminar -Study Group News -Over the Wall -Brief Notes -Youth Camp Cultivates Creativity -A Touch of Braille -Wilderness Retreat Welcomes Adventurers -International Corner (Hazel Tops, Rose Hens) -ARE Library News August, 1977 -Action Groups Enliven 45th Congress -Trustees Announce New Appointments (Hugh Lynn Cayce, Charles Thomas Cayce, Wilfred Sechrist) -Feedline -Bruce Bickham Newly Elected Trustee -ARE Library News -Library Building Fund -A Note of Thanks - Library Book Acquisition Fund -A Touch of Braille -Chiropractic Conference Convenes -International Corner -Over the Wall -Edgar Cayce on the Mystery of Jesus -Clinic Bulletin -Membership Message -Health and Beauty -Spa Week -Field Programs Across the Nation -HLC and Charles Thomas Cayce during a Congress Week break -Study Group News -Brief Notes September, 1977 -Congress Action Groups Present Proposals -Headquarters New Year's Conference Features: Dr. Raymond Moody, Dr. Daniel Goleman -Feedline -Brief Notes -Zahi Abass Hawass Tours U.S.A. -Fall Field Programs -Conference Reminder -International Circle -New Circulating Files -A Touch of Braille -Clinic Bulletin -Library Series Notice -Membership Message -Study Group News -Help Wanted for Prison Project -Over the Wall -Dream Incubation Project...Benefits Dreamers October, 1977 -Family Camp Fosters Creativity -Walene James' Book Receives Outstanding Reviews -Feedline -International Circle -Education Proposals Set by Congress -Health and Beauty -Over the Wall -A Touch of Braille -Wilderness Retreats: Alaska and the Rio Grande -Fall Field Programs -ARE Library News -Library Building Fund -Membership Message November, 1977 -Teams Active Across Nation -Expedition Explores in the Bahamas -Feedline -Clinic Bulletin -Field Programs, November-December 1977 -Brief Notes -Congress Action Proposals -Health and Beauty -Work-Study Program Featured in College Psych Course -Study Group News -Over the Wall -New Cooperating Doctors -A Touch of Braille: Dream Work -ARE Library Seeks Out-Of-Print Books -New Circulating File: The Spiritual Approach to Treating Specific Ailments -Enhance Tours Through Mexico Readings -Mexico Tour Applications -Jim Dixon Accepts Regional Representative Position December, 1977 -A First for the New Year Woman 1978 Congress Chairman (Dawn Ahart) -A Gift for the Meditation Room: Windows Created by Fredrica H. Fields -Feedline -A Report from the 1977 Post-Congress Committee -A Touch of Braille -Brief Notes (The Egypt Project, Special Asilomar Notice, International Retreat, Summer Staff Applications, Suppliers of Cayce Items) -1978 Winter Wilderness Retreats -Study Group News -Over the Wall -Sing a Song of Celebration (Stereo album recorded by Judith Stevens) -Health and Beauty -Field Programs: December and January -Membership Message -International Circle -Invitation to Research the Common Cold -Clinic Bulletin
    - A.R.E. News, 1978; Folder 6:6; Landers, Olive; Brittell, Katherine A.; January, 1978 -An Invitation to Congress -Easter Retreat: A Spiritual Renewal -Feedline -Plan Now for Summer Conferences -Health and Beauty -Clinic Bulletin -Membership Message -A Touch of Braille: Dream Work -Saco River Canoe Trip -Field Programs: February and March -Egyptian Involved in Work / Study Program (Ahmed Mawgoud) -Group of the Month (Washington, D.C. #1) -Cooperating Doctors Program Adds Psychologists and Psychiatric Social Workers -Over the Wall -ARE Camp Notices -Study Group News -ARE Library News -New Year's Resolutions -ARE Conference Focuses on Business Readings February, 1978 -Cayce Photographic Legacy Published (David Leary) -Marshall Resort Hotel Gets New Look: Winter Renovation Well Under Way -Feedline -Health and Beauty: The Common Cold -International Circle: International Retreat with Bill and Elsie Sechrist -A Touch of Braille -Summer Wilderness Retreats -Study Group News -Group of the Month (Hammond #1, Louisiana) -Field Programs -Letter from Member Serves as Example (Dorothy J. Fox) -Family Camps Expand -Clinic Bulletin -Membership Message -Two-Day Healing Symposium to be held in Los Angeles -ARE Library Seeks Out-of-Print Books March, 1978 -June Bro Joins A.R.E. Staff: Recalls Past with Edgar Cayce -Dr's Goleman and Moody Share Research Findings -Feedline -Limited Supply of Mullein Seeds Now Available -International Circle: Elsie and Bill Sechrist, International Representatives -Study Group News -Group of the Month (Enfield, Connecticut ARE Council) -Over the Wall -Clinic Bulletin -Youth Weeks Planned for ARE Camp -Field Programs June and July -ARE Florida Symposium -In Memoriam (Dora Harter) -Summer Youth Activities at Virginia Beach -ARE Library News -An Invitation from the Library to Aid in Care of Legacy -Tobacco Preserves Life April, 1978 -Dr. Cerminara Active in ARE -April Weekends at ARE Headquarters -Feedline -Membership Message -Membership Research: Project Israel (Joan S. Dombrowski) -New Regional Representative for State of Washington -Health and Beauty: Grape Juice for Dieting -Create a Spiritual Journey at ARE Camp -Congress Can Be A Goldmine (Dawn Ahart) -An Open Letter Re: Prison Spiritual Needs (Judith Stevens) -Study Group News -Group of the Month (Columbus #12, Ohio) -Field Programs -Doctor Shealy is Chairman of Organizing Committee: the American Holistic Medical Association -ARE Library News -Library Grateful for Gift Books -Library Acquires Hypnotic-Regression Transcripts -New Circulating File on Heart Enlargement -Circulating Files Index May, 1978 -Louis Boykin Accepts Position as ARE Personnel Manager -Sundance Community Dream Journal Extends Invitation -Feedline -Musician Applies Cayce Principles to Business Endeavor (Gail Sanderson) -Study Group News -Clinic Bulletin -Send a Messenger to Headquarters -Membership Message -Cooperating Doctors Program -New Referral Doctors -Group of the Month (Forest Lake No. 1, Minnesota) -Over the Wall -Seabeck Symposium '78 -Bring a Friend to: Asilomar, Toledo -Summer of 1978 A.U. Firsts -Second September Sailing Retreat -Health and Beauty: Massage -Eula Allen Tribute -A.U. 1978 Study Tour: Dream Journey with the Maya June, 1978 -Library / Conference Center Free of Debt -Smithsonian Psi Search Visits ARE -Feedline -Family Camp: A Live-in Application of Love -Group of the Month (Milwaukee No. 1, Wisconsin) -Clinic Bulletin -A Dream Come True: the ARE Library 1971-1975 -Membership Message -Field Programs -Summer Wilderness Retreat Openings -New Employment Form Available -Prayer Leaflet Joins the News -Study Group News -Over the Wall -A Thought for You; A Prayer for July -Cartoonist Uses Cayce Concepts in Business Endeavor (Gene Caporale) July, 1978 -ARE Clinic Initiates New Program (Temple Beautiful) -Hugh Lynn Cayce Lectures at Leisure World (Mesa, Arizona) -Feedline -Business Conference Planned for Fall -New Book on Edgar Cayce (Ann Neimark, With This Gift) -Health and Beauty: Mud Packs -Spa Week -ASFG Group of the Month (Poughkeepsie No. 1, New York) -Over the Wall -Study Group News -Counselor Recalls Camp Ideas -Memorial Camp Fund -A Thought for You -A Prayer for August -Field Programs -H.L. Cayce / A. Ogden in Wisconsin Program -Chicago Hosts Healing Symposium -Headquarters Offers One-Day Dream Special -Enjoy Psi Search: An Extra Special Summer Event -International Circle: International Retreat Cancelled -ARE Tours 1979 -Membership Message -Contributions, Prayer and Dreams Provide for A.J. Davis Boxes August, 1978 -ARE Members Head American Holistic Medical Association (Norman Shealy, William McGarey, Gladys McGarey, Lindsay Jacob) -Business Conference An October Event -Feedline -Principles of Ethics American Holistic Medical Association -Congress Isn't All Work (photographs) -announcement of ARE Board of Trustees Meeting (Hugh Lynn Cayce) -So You Thought You Were Too Busy: The Lunchtime Study Group -Field Programs -Bring a Friend: Philadelphia, Orlando -Dream Program Well Received -Study Group News -Over the Wall -A Thought for You -A Prayer for September September, 1978 -ARE Congress Creates Better Balance (Dawn Ahart) -Tribute to Eula Allen: A Joyous Occasion -Feedline -Pineal Gland Research Confirms Readings -Health and Beauty: The Sitz Bath -New Circulating File on Homosexuality Completes Research -Bring a Friend: ARE Headquarters, Asilomar, Mo Rance Retreat -International Circle -Field Programs -Hugh Lynn Cayce and Gina Cerminara Host Mid-South Symposium -Study Group News -Life Memberships Top the 400 Mark -ARE Clinic Announcement -Members Seek Creative Suggestions -A Thought for You -A Prayer for October -ASFG Group of the Month (New York #9) -14 Day Dream Cruise -Three New Trustees to Serve on ARE Board (Gerald Matlin, Lois McGee, Glenn Sanderfur) October, 1978 -ARE Headquarters New Year's Conference Features: Olga Worrall, Dr. George Ritchie -Temple Beautiful: A Holistic Center in Arizona -Feedline -Field Program Notices -An Interview with Dr. David Zink: An Explorer's Concern with Pre-History -Letter from ARE President Charles Thomas Cayce -ARE Projected Income and Expense Budget 1978 -Once Upon a Time at ARE Camp -ASFG Group of the Month (Lexington No. 2, Kentucky) -Over the Wall -Retirement Community to Open Near ARE -Health and Beauty -Study Group News -A Thought for You -A Prayer for November -Dreams Course Offered Across the Nation -Latest Circulating File on Healing Available November, 1978 -The Sechrists Visit Phillippines -Braille Library Looks Ahead (Alma Crovatt, Louise Rothrock) -Feedline -Experiences on an ARE Cascades Wilderness Trek (Sharon Mitchell) -Membership Message -Life After Birth: A Celebration of Healing (ARE Clinic's 12th Annual Symposium on Holistic Healing) -The Language of the Readings: An Inquiry (Gene Snyder) -Members Initiate Gutter Fund -A Thought for You; A Prayer for December -ASFG Group of the Month (Los Angeles No. 3) -Over the Wall -Health and Beauty: Senna -Field Programs -In Memoriam: Jeff Coats -A Member's Search (Milford D. Waltner) December, 1978 -A Christmas Eve Gift (letter from Braille library user Ken Hurley) -The Birth of the Master (selections from the EC Readings by Ruth LeNoir) -Feedline -Congress Sharing Group Becomes Child Education Committee -Summer Staff Applications -ASFG Group of the Month (Tucson No. 7, Arizona) -Over the Wall -A Thought for You; A Prayer for January -Study Group News -An Interview with Michael Dennis: 1979 Congress Chairman -Field Programs -1979 Wilderness Retreats -Letter from Hugh Lynn Cayce about ARE Board of Trustees